Let's now talk about Tooltips, Popovers, and Models.
接下来让我们学习有关 工具提示 弹出框和模态框的相关知识
These are three different ways of showing content to the users.
这是三种不同的向用户呈现 网站内容的方法
Earlier we had seen the use of the collapse
在此之前 我们学习过如何应用折叠插件
Plugin where we were able to show and hide content on the webpage.
来显示和隐藏网页的某些内容
But in those applications
不过在那些场合中 我们要求那些内容
we had to have the content already embedded in the webpage.
都是已经嵌入了网页中的内容
Tooltips, popovers, and modals are the way of overlaying content onto your webpage.
而工具提示 弹出框和模态框都是 在你网页的上面覆盖一层内容
In terms of flexibility, tooltips are the simplest, but
在易用性和灵活性方面 工具提示是最容易应用的
provide very little flexibility.
但同时它也比较"死板"
Popovers provide more flexibility than tooltips.
相比之下 弹出框就更"灵活"
Modals are, of course, a comprehensive way of presenting information to the users.
至于模态框 自然就是一个很广泛的 向用户呈现内容的方法
So we'll examine each of these In more detail, next.
接下来我们将会学习这三者的 更细节的东西
To understand how tool tips work, let's visit our web page.
为了让你知道工具提示是怎么样的 让我们看一个栗子吧
And, then when we hover onto the reserve table button,
当我们把我们的鼠标悬停在这个 Reserve Table 按钮上面时
you can see that a message pops up on our web page.
你可以看到网页上浮现了一条信息
This is enabled using a tooltip.
这个效果就是用工具提示实现的
Tooltips are a simple way of presenting some information to the users.
工具提示是一个很简单的 呈现信息给用户的方法
A tooltip pops up whenever the users hovers onto a button or
正如我们刚刚看到的 工具提示通常 会在某些按钮或链接处应用
a link to which the tooltip has been added.
当你把鼠标悬停其上 就会有相应的内容浮现出来
To add a tooltip to an a tag or a button tag you will add three attributes.
实现工具提示的方法是对一个 a 标签或一个 button 标签应用三项属性
The first one, data toggle is equal to tooltip
第一个 是 data-toggle="tooltip"
specifies that the tooltip has been added to the bottom tag.
它将会把相应的 a 标签或 button 标签 变成一个工具提示
The second attribute,
第二项要设置的属性
the title gives the message string that'll be shown inside the tooltip.
则是 title="xxx" 其中 xxx 就是你想显示的内容
The third attribute is data placement, which is either top,
第三个 是 data-placement="xxx"
bottom, left, or right.
其中 xxx是 "top", "buttom", "left", "right" 之一
And this specifies which direction the tooltip is going to pop up.
分别代表着该工具提示将会出现在 上面 下面 左边和右边
For the tooltip to work correctly, you will also need to include a small
为了让这个工具提示正确地运作
amount of JavaScript code at the end of your page.
你还需要加进一小些 JavaScript 代码
Right after where you import the bootstrap
这些代码要包在 script 标签中
JavaScript classes, you will include the script shown here.
并放在你引入 Bootstrap JavaScript 类 的代码的下面
This script specifies that for all those
这段代码的作用是告诉机器
tags to which the data toggle tooltip attribute has been added,
当一切准备妥当后 让所有 data-toggle 属性为 tooltip 的元素
the tooltip will be enabled.
运行一下 .tooltip 方法 从而得以激活 各个工具提示元件
Looking at the example of how you allow tooltip to a on a button tag.
让我们看一个用 a 标签 实现工具提示的栗子
Here, I have ironed the tooltip to the a tag, by adding the data-toggle.
你可以看到我对这个 a 标签设置了 data-toggle="tooltip"
And the data placement and the title to the a tag here.
然后还正确设置了 data-placement 属性和 title 属性
This is what causes the tooltip to be
这些将会正确地配置好一个 工具提示元件
popped up when you have it on to the button in our webpage.
然后当你的鼠标悬停在这个元件之上时 其效果将会如右上图所示
Popovers, are a generalization of tooltips.
下面让我们来学习弹出框 它比较像是工具提示的拓展版
Popovers allow you to present both a title as well as the content in the popover.
弹出框允许你同时呈现 "标题"和"内容"这两部分
The title will be presented in bold at the top, and
其标题将会加粗显示在其上
the content will be included at the bottom of the popover.
然后内容自然就是 呈现在标题之下
Popovers have to be also enabled explicitly by including the JavaScript
同样的 弹出框需要一定的 JavaScript 代码
code shown in there into our web page.
来保证其正确运作
So as an example this is what a popover will
那么右上图就是一个弹出框的栗子
look like when you click on the button.
当你点击那个按钮时 它就会弹出这么一个小框
So in this case we have associated the popover with this button here,
在这个栗子里 我们是用 button 标签来实现弹出框的
by including the data toggle as popover.
与工具提示类似 你需要设置 data-toggle="popover"
The title with the information over displayed in the popovers title, and
然后在 title 属性中键入 弹出框的标题内容
the data content carries the information to be displayed in the content part
在 data-content 属性中
of the popover.
键入弹出框的键入主体内容
Now the popover also can take placement
同样的 弹出框可以 设置 data-placement 属性
attribute which specifies which side a popover should be shown.
它将会控制这个弹出框出现的位置
In this example the popover will
注意在这个栗子里 你需要点击按钮
be triggered when you click on the button, unlike tooltips,
才能激活弹出框 这和之前的工具提示不同
which will automatically appear when you hover onto the button or the link.
因为之前的工具提示是 你鼠标悬停其上后便能自动激发
The popover has to be triggered by clicking on the button or the link.
弹出框则必须通过点击才能激发
And next time when you click again on the button
然后当你再次点击时
of the link the popover will be hidden.
相应弹出框则会消失
So the popover will remain open until you click again onto the button of the link.
这也意味着 直到你再次点击 弹出框都不会消失
Modals are a more gentle way of presenting information to the users.
而模态框则是一个相当优雅的 呈现信息给用户的方法
Modals allow you to define the information to represented in a lot more detail.
毕竟模态框能让你定制很多细节
You can even format the information and
你甚至可以用各种各样的 HTML 代码
specify the information in the form of many HTML code.
来定制你想展现的内容的格式
The models contain both a header, body, and a footer.
一个模态框通常包含 一个抬头 一个页脚
Typically, you will include most of the information in the body of the message.
以及一块主题内容
The footer is usually used to include buttons,
通常的做法是在页脚处放一些按钮
maybe cancel or an action button, okay?
比如说"取消"或者"提交"什么的
The header usually carries some information about the specific modal.
而抬头则一般会携带 该模态框的概述之类的信息
Let's look at an example and then come back and examine how we create a modal.
接下来让我们先看一个栗子 然后再看看其具体实现
Going back to our web page, all right?
回到我们的网页吧
You can see that there is a log in link on the right side of the Nav bar.
你可以看到导航栏的右侧 有一个 login 链接
When you click on it, a modal will pop up.
当你单击它 一个模态框就会显现
So you see that I have designed this modal to include their
这个模态框的内容 就是我们之前
log in form that previously existed in the nav bar.
放在导航栏里的登录表格的内容
So I have moved the form into this modal here.
也就是说 我把那个登录表格 移植到了这个模态框中
So here, in this modal, we can see that there is a header and
在这个模态框里 我们能看到一个抬头
the body of the model contains the font.
以及其主体内容 也就是一个登录表格
This particular example doesn't have a footer.
在这个栗子里 我没有实现页脚
Now looking at the modal example,
让我们来看看其实现方法吧
you see that the modal is created by defining a div, and
你可以看到最外层是一个 div 然后我们对这个 div 设置了
giving it an ID, and the class to be given to the div is modal.
class="modal" 并给了它一个 id
If you want the modal to fade in when the button or
如果你想让这个模态框有个 渐入的动画效果
the a tag is clicked, then we give the fade class also to the modal.
你就可以设置 class="modal fade"
Inside the modal, we'll have an inner div with the modal dialogue class.
在这最外层 div 里面 则是一个设置了 class="modal-dialog" 的 div
In addition you can specify the size of the modal as modal hyphen lg or
特别的 你可以通过 modal-lg 或 modal-sm
modal hyphen sm.
来定制该模态框的大小
The default size would be invoked if you do not specify the size.
如果你没有特别指定其大小 系统会设置其为默认大小
The modal also includes an inner div.
然后再其内则又是一个 div
The modal content.
对其要设置 class="modal-content"
Now inside the modal content div you would include the header, body and the footer.
然后在这个 div 里面 就是我们的 抬头, 主体内容和页脚了
The header will be another div with the class model header.
这三部分的每一部分 都是一个单独的设置不同的 div
The body will be a div with the class model body and then, of course,
抬头就是设置 class="modal-header" 主体内容则是 class="modal-body"
the footer will be a div with the class modal footer.
页脚则是 class="modal-footer"
Now, in this example, we are going to include the form HTML
在这个栗子里 我们在主体内容中
code inside the modal body of this particular modal.
放了一个登录表格
How do you trigger the modal?
那么该怎么激发这个模态框呢 ?
To do that, you need to include in the information in either the a tag.
你需要在一个 a 标签或一个 button 标签中
A button tag.
设置一些相应的内容
So to an A tag or a button tag you will give the data toggle as a modal, and
你需要设置 data-toggle="modal"
the data target will be the ID of the modal to be specified.
以及 data-target="#xxx" 其中 xxx 是你之前为你模态框设置的 id
So in this example, the login modal's ID is specified as the data target.
在这个栗子里 我将这个模态框的 id 设置为了 loginModal
So that's why when the link, the login link on the and
所以对应的 我在 a 标签中 设置了 data-target="#loginModal"
navbar is clicked, the modal pops up onto the webpage.
于是当你点击这个 a 标签对应的按钮时 这个模态框就会显现在屏幕上
We'll now move on to the next exercise.
接下来我们将会进行一个练习
While we're there we will consider tooltips and modals.
我们将会亲自实现工具提示和模态框
So we introduce a tooltip so that when the user hovers onto to the reserve table
实现后的效果将会和这节课
button, the tooltip also pops up.
之前展示的效果一致
In addition, we'll have the login form enclosed inside a modal,
亦即当你鼠标悬停在 Reserve Table 按钮上时 一个工具提示会被自动激发
and so when the user clicks on the login button in the nav bar,
以及当你点击导航栏中的 login 按钮时 一个封装了一个登录表格的模态框
the modal will pop up on the screen.
会显现在屏幕上 【翻译 - Carefree0910】